# **Data Scientist | Technical Business Analyst**

maggimckenzie@gmail.com | (615) 294-6902 | www.linkedin.com/in/maggi-mckenzie

## **Professional Summary**

Dedicated professional with over 25 years' experience in a fast-paced, sales-driven environment. I'm excited every day to dig into tough problems to provide solutions. My goals are to make systems better for the people who use them and answer critical questions through analyzing complex data.

## Strengths & Skills

Languages:	SQL   Python   R   VBA   ABAP/4	
IT   Technical:	Requirements gathering   analysis	QA   post-deployment support
ETL  data mapping	Backlog prioritization	Schema design
Functional and technical specs	Wireframes   mockups	Troubleshooting
IT   SAP:	Customer hierarchy implementation	Light ABAP development
Sales and Distribution (SD)	Order to Cash (OTC)	Materials Management (MM)
Financial Accounting (FI)	ABAP/4 query development	Pricing procedure config
IDOCs and external interfaces	SIS custom structure config	
Compensation   Accounting:	Excel   Access	Word   Powerpoint
Sales compensation management Extensive reporting   analysis	Payroll   ADP general knowledge	Management experience

### Experience

#### Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN | 09/2020 to 06/2021

#### **Data Science Bootcamp**

Nine-month intensive course in Python, R, and SQL with practical application and hands-on development projects for partner companies and organizations.

#### **Individual Projects**

 Winning Strategies for Jeopardy! – R Shiny app exploring historical Jeopardy! categories, clues, answers, and winning scores; used Python/BeautifulSoup to scrape this dataset from j-archive.com.
 RShiny App

GitHub

#### **Team Projects**

- Provider Communities in Nashville Analysis of relationships between Nashville hospitals and referring providers from a Medicare dataset using Python, PostgreSQL, and Neo4J.
   Group Presentation
- People3 Demographic Comparison App R Shiny app that compares a company's workforce to regional demographics; used R tidyverse/tidycensus to retrieve this data from the US Census.
- COVID-19 Order Violation Analysis used data from hub.nashville.gov to analyze reported violations and COVID clusters with Python geospatial and analytical tools.

 Tennessee Earthquake Impact Assessment – analyzed historical earthquake data with Python geospatial and analytical tools.

#### ClarisHealth | Nashville, TN | 07/2020 to Present

#### **ETL Team Technical Business Analyst**

- Gather requirements, support ETL development, conduct QA on large-scale data implementations for internal and external clients.
- Data mapping and associated data quality analysis for onboarding new clients using ClarisHealth's Pareo payment integrity software and solutions.

#### Southwestern Fundraising (Great American Opportunities) | Nashville, TN | 09/1993 to 04/2020

#### Compensation Manager – 2017 to 2020

- Audited 100% of commission accounts to identify and implement needed controls, process changes, and reporting changes.
- Improved calculation processes and payroll interfaces to eliminate errors and reduce cycle time: eliminated two
  weeks from year-end expense plan closeout; eliminated two weeks from year-end commission closeout.
- Calculated all monthly, seasonal, and annual commission, bonuses, incentives, allowances for ±275 salespeople and managers.
- Established and managed monthly salesperson draws and advances against projected commission income to prevent overdraws
- Managed accountable expense plan according to company and IRS guidelines (managed one compensation accountant).
- Transitioned all processes and systems from employee salesperson model to independent salesperson model.
   Developed new commission system and managed runout of sales compensation from the old system.
- Developed & prepared compensation projections, analysis, management reporting, monthly accruals for CFO, accounting, and sales management team.

#### Sr. Business Analyst – 2000 to 2017

- Member of SAP lead resource team for all company processes.
- Integrated multiple Microsoft .NET and SQL Server systems with SAP.
- Developed standardized processes to streamline data and systems integration for multiple company acquisitions.
- Improved and automated publisher processing function to reduce weekly cycle time from 4 days to 1.5 days.
- Analyzed recurring pricing errors in master data setup and implemented validation procedures to eliminate them.
- Performed large volumes of ad-hoc data analysis, sales statistics, customer information, performance tracking,
   from both SAP and SQL databases using ABAP query, SSMS, Excel, and Access.
- Extensive SAP LSMW development.
- High-volume support and troubleshooting, especially SAP SD/Order to Cash process: partner functions, pricing, contract, sales order, delivery from multiple shipping points, billing, accounting interface.
- Managed material master data setup and pricing master data setup (managed two analysts).

- Designed, configured, and implemented SAP statistical structures (SIS), including:
  - Sales, pricing, and participant data.
  - o Replicating/summarizing transactional data to statistical structures.
  - o Designing internal and customer-facing reports, downloads/exports, dashboards, and scoreboards.
  - Designing/configuring reporting structures for all sales statistics and commission payments to salespeople. Included reporting against multiple multi-level hierarchies/management structures/commission rate structures.
- Developed, supported, and maintained:
  - o SAP and related processes for catalog pricing setup and validation.
  - Product and sales forecasting systems.
  - Salesperson commission system.
  - Magazine subscription/publisher fulfillment processing system.
- Gathered requirements, prepared specs & wireframes, tested, and provided support for:
  - o All types of internal and customer facing paperwork and reports.
  - o Routing and transit functions for multiple distribution centers.
  - Pick/pack and cubing functions for multiple distribution centers.
  - High volume order form scanning and data entry systems.
  - o External vendor interfaces, including EDI and SAP automated PO processing.
  - SAP custom transactions, dashboards, consoles.
  - Company online school fundraising platforms, including payment and credit card processing.
- Additional support for SAP MM: material setup, configuration, bills of material, info records, purchase order, purchase req, automated PO processing, vendor setup.

**Business Systems Specialist** – **1997 to 2000** - Initial SAP implementation team, sales reporting lead, responsible for design and implementation of all sales statistics using custom SAP SIS structures.

Administrative Assistant - 1993 to 1997 - Assistant to Corporate Vice President & Treasurer.

### **Education**

Nashville Software School | Data Science Bootcamp

Centenary College of Louisiana | BA in English | Summa Cum Laude